Il Cafe We have you
covered When was the last time you were in a
counter and a checkout queue
Somewhere that the way you transact and the way you
sort of behave as a customer and consumer
of a product has changed in the last five
years Well turns out that I've taken
stock of myself several times over I'm pretty
excited about this conversation on Il
Cafe Today welcome to the show my name is
Sheetal this is a podcast that is by
ICICI Lombard and we are about to
understand customer centricity as a crushing
imperative in the ICICI Lombard world
as the effort is to improve access to these
products and solutions Now customer
centric innovations have been at the very
heart of what the organization has done in terms of
its product office over the years right
from the early days through to the
period of digitization  That we are all part
of to the present day today on oil cafe we
are going to call on the heavy weight to help us
understand this a little bit better we've got someone
with over two decades of experience as a
professional and certainly nine years at
ICICI Lombard part of customer
support she is in fact the head of customer
support at ICICI Lombard Vasundhara
Bhosale is here to chat us up on the subject
of customer centricity nice to have you here
Vasundhara and welcome to oil cafe how are you thank you thank you
sheetal thank you very much very well
and very very excited and
happy to be here to share my thoughts on
customer centricity and what we are doing
at ICS lord i am just going to ask a
lighter question to start with have you also evolved
as a customer do you also do what i
spoke of  Right up front on the show yes yes absolutely I have
a tough time
refusing telemarketing calls for
example I have a tough time refusing
survey feedback for example because all of
those things have become an integral part
and and I understand the importance of all of that
from the customer for the customer
support teams for the organization so that's something that
I struggle with and yes
times have changed life has changed when I
started working we used to everybody would take
calls and anybody would do what ever they
wanted to do with the customer and from there to you know where we are today a
through the whole
gamut of evolving systems and
processes and when we started
working there were no CRL and today you can't even imagine
life without then so it's been
a big shift or absolutely a big shift
and clearly it  Become an art, a science,
you know, nothing about it anymore,
innovations are becoming of it, this kind of thinking
and data insight that we have, what if I may ask you, it is
a driving philosophy when we talk about
ICS, lumber and
customer centricity, right, why is it the
central pillar in the organization's vision and
mission for any organization that wants to take care
of all its shareholders and
especially their customers, customer centricity
is an essential pillar of any kind of vision
and mission that the organization has, and it goes without saying,
and by prioritizing
customer centricity, any
organization can actually deliver
innovative solutions for customers, otherwise you know, you
can stay in your cocoon and not even feel when
the world takes over, so to
understand customers' needs, to
understand their changing behaviors, to
understand their changing needs  To
understand the landscape around the customer, how they are
experiencing other industries,
not just your industry, and how that is
changing their experience from you as an
organization. All of that is a central
part of being customer-centric as an
organization, and customer centricity is
ultimately what gets you more customers, and it
helps you retain your current customers
and get more business from them. And yes, I
mean, to add value to the customer journey with
us, is what actually makes all the difference,
or absolutely, and an area like this, where
ICs are lumped, is a key player, indeed, is something that
really touches the emotional core of these
people. So, all the more, you know, I would imagine
responsibility on shoulders to get it right. Now, we just
spoke about the then, and now,
some time back, Vasundhara, you know how things were back then,
at set, and clearly, it is a
well-known fact that  Customer needs have
changed over the years so how does ICS lumber
factor these changes and keep pace with
the requirements did you mention that there is a way in which
you collect data and
insights as well you mentioned those calls for
example being an important pipeline to
insights like that but I'm sure these things have
changed a lot since that time and then how does
a company then take all of this data
and make sure it you know sort of
translates those into actual products that
speak to those needs of the customer great
question Sheetal thank you so one is that yes
you look at products and you know you are
increasingly putting out products out
in the market which are digitally available which are easy
for the customer to purchase and
experience beside that what you also end up doing is that
you know a lot
Lots of our customers all over the world now, especially after
the lockdown and the COVID, have adopted
digital solutions very, very much like Facebook
to the bottom right. People are on instant messaging
platforms. Can't imagine life without them anymore
and customers expect that the
businesses will also communicate with them the way they
communicate with their family and
friends. And these channels have become channels
of convenience and you can't stay away from them as
businesses do. Well, we are also doing the same.
Leveraging technology, we are
building service capabilities and we are
introducing lots of solutions for customer
journeys and improving engagement
mechanisms with our customers. When our
customers understand the natural language of
the customer, which is technically called NLP
enablement. We have artificial intelligence
and AI based chat bots. We have voice bots.
We have solutions on the  IVR we have
visual IVR where you know one the customer is
on call with you you only you have the customer
through the links and through the internet so all of these
kinds of solutions we have put
out there in the market our customers are
experiencing them every day we get feedback
from them and we keep evolving them we have an app which is called
oil take care we have
very innovative solutions no oil take care
something from normal you know claim launching
and claim status at what customers can also do
is available features like you know you can
scan your face and get your
vitals and you know you know how your doing key
health vitals so to speak blood pressure and
things like that so it's really
fantastic to see customers using all of these and then and that sort of thing sounds very exciting
to me I
think and spoke about it  With Girish some
time back as well and I think the reference that came up was
samosa for some reason I remember
samosa mango like oh my god imagine
samosa looking at you and say I am samosa
and if you eat me then you will become fat and
something like that at so what technology
can do and how it can engage with people but
I am going to come to the engagement part a
little bit later take that you are very
excited about you know personally Vasundhara something that is
going to really revolutionize
is you mention a few of those of course
everybody is talking about AI generative AI
NLP is part of that whole customer
experience behavior tracking and so on anything else that
you are very gung ho about it is
going to have a role to play in
product needs of consumers or Shar Sheetal
so like I mention we have buts and  Voice
but the chat bots we
created as assistants but what Riya
actually is an AI powered chat but she has
ml nlp capability and she helps us
streamline communication and our
customers experience through DIY
journeys now Riya we celebrated her
first birthday on one day this year so she
is already one year more than one year old so much more
girl and she is she is like she is a
human avatar and design a human avatar
Riya she changes her appearance based on
festivals and independence day things like that so we
tried to keep a human and she
can be accessed through our website through
[music]
comfortable in understanding natural
language in fact the progress we are making
is to get Riya to start talking in
Hindi and you know this there are lots of intent
training modules intent mining modules
for for a better conversation experience
with the customers we Riya  Is concern so much of
that is really taking shape has taken shape
over last one year plus because those are what they learn from
the experience as a human being so so in a
sense you know when you chat with
Riya it is like chatting with a human being
so accept that you know one of the
parties is a but it is an evolving but it
mixes with the behaviour Riya is also
intended to do so Riya what she does is provide
convenient you know easy to access all
the time available kind of customer support
for customers she is able to take claims if
customers have claim requests she is able
to share you know hospitals and network
groups and she is able to give you claim
statuses she is able to take
endorsement requests and give you
endorsed copies she is able to give you
policy copies she is she is able to do all of these
things also  Understand
your coverage and benefits. If you want to
understand, renew your policy quickly.
You know within a few clicks. All of these
things. So, Ria has been actually quite,
warmly accepted by our customers, and
we are very excited by the opportunity that
Ria presents for the future. She talks about more than a million
customers every month. So, that's what she's done.
By the phenomenal success that this
particular intervention has brought for the
organization. And I was just thinking about
apps and trusting those things have become
sort of integrated. My mother, I just
booked her tickets for something, and the
first question she asked me was, I
downloaded the airline's app, and I'm like, why do you need it?
You get the email. The text, no,
no, the app is like, you know, I'll have the app, so I
just open it, and it will be.  There right so it's really
what an A can actually do it can
translate into pure trust in their head
and this is a 75 year old woman I'm
talking about but in any case you know what are some of the
learning that I'll take care of is
given you RIA has given you that you think are going to be
critical in what you do in the
future so what I'll take for example is it's
able to customize personalize your
experience with the organization you know otherwise
you really don't feel so connected with the
company especially our kind of business where you come
to us only if you have a problem and we say that you don't need to come
to us but yes these
people come to us they don't break down and
they have to go to the hospital and things like that so
for I'll take care of you to be there with
the customer when they are in the time of  It makes a lot
of difference to the customer
experience and it is designed to offer
personalized solutions to the customer and get to their
unique needs so that makes it very relevant
for each and every individual
and empowers the customer with you know once it's a one
stop solution one window wherever you know you can do everything that you want to do whether it's
policy related and claim related what it also does which is more
proactive than like I was saying that
you a customer generally comes to one they are in a
situation but what I take care of does
differently than a normal insurance business
is to provide care to the customers wellness
needs you know so many of those things are very
proactive and those are things if the
customers engage with the on wellness needs that
really helps the customer maintain the
medical  History has made better lifestyle
choices and two are things that I think not
only does it help us engage with customers
but it also helps us actually add value to a
customer's life and become more relevant to the
customer. So, by providing such tailor-made
solutions, we not only improve customer
satisfaction, but also
tech-based solutions, you know, they help you be
relevant and stay relevant and be able to
analyze customer behavior and behavioral
patterns because you get more information and
data from customers. So, that helps us
enhance and streamline systems, product, and service offerings
in the future. And even solution service
offerings like what RIA does depend on what
customers are looking for or if I take care of them.
In the future, it helps us prioritize the
solutions that we want to put out there in the
market and helps be more relevant and
target products better and stay more relevant to the
customer's life.  Keep our sales
relevant to customers or so what I'm
hearing is that you know engaging with
the customer clearly this is these are
times continue our engagement is really the key
to figuring out what to do next
and how to do it better but what I'm really doing is for example
to reach
out and educate the customers on a regular
basis you mention the oil take care of or some other cool interesting
intervention that you
thought were like wow why do we think of this alright a
very famous adage no it jungle me mor nacha kisne dekha sots something that we keep talking about
internally also like you can put lots of
solutions out there but if you
really don't get to the customer and say hey you
can do this it does really help right so so yes
your absolutely correct two it's a  Very very
relevant question don't you know how we get
telling the customer do you know you can do all this with
us so we have launched a lot of campaigns for
this for this kind of education of the customer
and not only of the customer but our channel
partners our sales teams our branch
teams etc so we have hashtags etc which
is empower the customer so where are we telling our own
employees and how to empower the customer which means then the
customer can do things the sales they are not
dependent on anybody for
or come to a branch and call up sub or no they are
empowered to do a lot of things things are
available now and I will take care and you at their
finger tips literally so then we also have the
power the partner which is tp you know because we have given
a lot of services
out there for partners as well on their buts
and on their platform to them  Engage with us
on to be able to service customers because a
lot of customers in our industry approach the
agent for their servicing needs so they are also
pushed out to the partner so the
partner services the customer directly instead
of trying to say okay I've taken
your request I will get in touch with the
company and get something done even if that's out you know so
ETC was empower the customer
ETP was empower the partner we also have
DIY campaigns which is tell the
customers and how they can do things
damsels we have a lot of videos for
customers so for example if you if you come
and say okay I need to claim something and you
start a claim process with us the first
thing you get is a video where we tell you
what to expect in the whole process because
a lot of people start with the claim
but they don't know what to expect next
What's going to happen you have to give documents are they going to tell me when are they going to tell
me is it going to be today tomorrow the
days five days 15 days what is it going to be
so the videos you know sets expectations
correctly tells you what claim number to
hold on to one to get in touch with us one
can you expect payment and things
like that so those kind of education things like I know I
used but for example now general
eras also has to do KYC with the customer
so we launched videos to tell the customer now the
KYC process and how they can get their
KYC done with us and they are interacting with the
video so you can actually have clicks
available on the video so if you want to
intervene somebody you can actually do that
through the video and we've had really
impressive engagement rates  On the video so
almost 52% engagement rates which our
partners who are working on the video are very very pleasant
surprised by that kind of
number because we are trying to
inject the video at the right place at the right
the relevant opportunity instead of just
you know burdening every customer with it like if
you don't have a claim with us I
send you claim education video you are not going to really do much about it keep it on the
side
for the future and may not do that as well so we try to
intervene at the
right place educate at the right time so that kind of
assistant we are giving utilizing all the kind
of facility and faculties I am
really helping in like empowering our
customers that's what we actually
believe in you know engage and empower the customer
so that you know they are absolutely  Smooth journey
I am glad that you brought up that otherwise
you no painful part of that customer
experience which is usually the claim
process and the way in which you are working
around and through the claim process to even
engage with the customer through that interesting anything else
you want to call out Vasundhara
in terms of the claim process because I do
believe there are people out there who wanna know okay all this is very well this
jungle me mor
nacha Madhumati ka song you piddled out for us
over r but tell me a little bit more about this
part so we are all sure of breathing a bit more easier
sher the AI ​​based claim
processing and AI based and ML based
claim processing is quick easy swift
for the customer so for example customer can
intimate claim on RIA on
smaller process now we've done away with a lot
of  Frills and kept them for later so it's
very easy and quick to latch a claim with us
and then for us to fulfill that claim for
you and to service you through the claim so for
example you can actually do the video of
your vehicle and send it to us and then we
process the claim on that on the basis of
that video AI has reduced cashless
health claim request approval time so that kind of
changes those kind of
benefits for the customers we have been able to rival this
initiative this kind of fast
decision making on cashless it enables the
treatment to really start quickly and
it reduces the customers anxiety time the wait time that they otherwise you know they like
panicking whether it goes to happen or not
and so we reduce that time emergency
situation you need to be out there for the
customer and do it  Really quickly the visual
IVR that I was talking about Arlia
is a platform that provides seamless
claim intimation you know and especially for
motor insurance customers like you say if you
call up the call center motor insurance claim
registration is super smooth much shorter than it used to be so
the processes also we
work on and made them much easier the
bed guides you at every step and it
collects all the information real time basis it
goes to the claims team there is no wait
time and there is no scheduler running
and things like that everything is happening
seamlessly and real time so we offer solution
24/7 because it's on our 24/7 call center
number voice but plus our team of call center
folks is available there to help customers additionally
customers can track their health claim and
motor claim status real time it's very
helpful for them like I said Arlia
Helps no they can go to the website and check they can go
to all take care and check it takes
care of you know the anta claim process
from start to and these kinds of things
really help what does the future look like if I were to
sort of ask you to train your
vision into the next five 10 year window
from customer behavior here and now and the kinds of
technologies that are underway what do
you expect what do you see the road map
look like for ic labada the way the world
is evolving and the way the technology is
evolving I don't think anybody can give you a
five 10 year window into anything at all so it's very exciting
to see chat GPT happen we're trying to see how to
leverage
char GPT for example so these kinds of
things are so much you know just one day something gets lost
and it just changes your your
plan for the year so  Forget the five-year and
the 10-year window, like you repeated, and I
shared that it's very exciting times
for all of us. You know, in any kind of field,
I think the way technology is disrupting your
plans every day, it's really exciting, but what we want to do is what we have
signed
up for is to continuously work closely on
what ever new technology is, whether it's AI or
robotics. You know, enable what ever new
solutions people are coming up with. We sign up for
experimenting with what we promise all and what we
promise our customers. We want to stay
continuously focused on
building robust solutions and business models that
stand on these solid pillars of one,
prudent risk management, that's the key to our
business. We're very technology-driven, in-
your-face solutions for our customers, our channel
partners, and the enterprise network. We
have a huge team of very, very passionate people.  It's the
work of our employees, and I think we have the trust
of our customers. They're always at the
forefront of things. We keep looking at it. It makes it all the more exciting.
And so, I
think the future is just exciting. Nobody can give you a
five-year, 10-year window.
So, the road map is clear. Customers can
stay in the middle, and we keep working and
experimenting. So, until the time comes, we keep doing that. I think we're
on a roll. You know, no one thing
I'm sure of is going to happen in the
next 10 years, but we can't.  Talk about anything else there are going to be a lot more
cups in the background over there for you in
not your award so proud of them I can share them out there
for every buddy to see our teams are very
excited to always go out and
keep showcasing what we are doing because
you know the world is not true that you you keep
your close and say ok I am doing this I don't want to share it
with anybody because you have to go out there talk about
things and then
you learn three more
things ultimately your
unique connect lies in your passionate people in
your capability and capacity to
experiment in your risk taking
abilities nobody can copy that at all so never shy away
from sharing and getting together are
fantastic and here wishing you many more
of those you and the team and thank you so much
Vasundhara for making this quiet  A such a
delightful experience you know master
story tellers I must set because now I will never listen to this
song in the jungle more
customer centricity
an economic way in
pleasure talking to you and I hope this also goes towards
educating our employees
not what they can expect to see
and what they can expect driving customer centricity
respect of the function they are in so thank
you so many great questions
holy became able to answer them and throw some light on them
and let the best to every buddy working no
of it thank you listening to il cafe we
have you covered